Job Scope

- · Mechanical Engineer
- · Sales Engineer
- Automation Engineer (PLC)

Technical Skills

Machine System Troubleshooting

Mechanical Installation

Human Machine Interface (HMI) Training

Electrical Wiring

PCB Soldering

Microsoft Excel

Languages

English

Chinese

Malay

Ch'ng Kha Leong

Sales Engineer

Chinese, Malaysian Bukit Mertajam, 14000, Malaysia 012-4328185

leong 0318@outlook.com



Profile

Sales Engineer for CNC machines at CK Mac Sdn Bhd (formerly EME Machinery Sdn Bhd), Penang, Malaysia

July 2017 - Present

Started as technician role which initially provides repair and maintenence for CNC machines, currently working as sales engineer in CK Mac Sdn Bhd, a local CNC system solution industry. As sales engineer, have considerable experience in promoting products to the customers based on their needs. Also provide software training (such as HMI), technical repair & maintenance service and consultancy.

Employment history

Sales Engineer for CNC machines at CK Mac Sdn Bhd, Penang, Malaysia

July 2017 - Present

- Promoting and selling company products to customers based on their requirements as primary role.
- Provide technical consultancy and specifications related to company products (such as CNC, milling, turning machines).
- Provide technical troubleshooting, repair, maintenance & support to customers in needs.
- Provide technical training such as HMI, machine repair, etc.
- Schedule appointments with customers for requirements briefing.
- Search for potential customers for the company.
- Manage logistics and delivery to ensure machines are delivered to the customers on a timely basis.
- · Manage price negotiations and deals with the customers.
- Responsible for managing and arranging techicians for customer support.

Technician for CNC machines at EME Machinery Sdn Bhd, Penang, Malaysia

July 2014 - June 2017

- Machinery installation and assembly for customers.
- Electrical wiring and assembly.
- PCB soldering and troubleshooting.
- Provide technical troubleshooting, repair, maintenance & support to customers in needs.
- Provide technical training such as HMI, machine repair, etc.

Kerian Cemerlang Trading, Perak, Malaysia

Sept 2013 - June 2014

Gas delivery

Education

Secondary/SPM/"O" Level, SMK Taman Perwira, Bukit Mertajam

2009 - 2010

- Field of study: Science
- 9 Credits (1 B, 2 C, 1 D, 5 G)

Lower Secondary Education Level/PMR, SMK Taman Perwira, Bukit Mertajam

2005 - 2008

Activities

Malaysia Technology Expo

2018

Company exhibition

Metaltech

2018

Company exhibition

Fanuc/Mitsubishi Application Technical Training

2018

• Company Training